Vimanshu Raj Chandra

Professional Summary

Flexible student with great communication skills seeks job opportunities to expand work experience. Works well under pressure, adaptable, and ready to be a strong team player. Willing to take on any task to support the team and help business succeed. Offers strong work ethic and problem solving abilities.

Skills

- Research participant relations
- Experimental results documentation
- Survey coding
- Strong communication
- Data collection
- Statistical analysis
- Python
- mysql

Experience

Undergraduate Research Assistant, - at UPES

JAN 2020 - MAY 2020

- Ran ML specific experiments in support of department research and reported problems to faculty.
- Helped faculty obtain deeper insights into research with use of different analytical techniques using python, numpy and various other ML libraries.
- Compiled, cleaned, and modeled research data.

Teaching assistant, - at local NGO

JAN 2020 - MAY 2020

- Independently supervised class 6th students in Mathematics in their local language.
- Provided education materials, weekend lesson plans and took doubt sessions.

EDUCATION

University of Petroleum and Energy Studies, Dehradun, India – Bachelor of Technology

May 2016 - MAY 2020, Dehardun

Computer science engineering with specialization in business analytics and optimization done from IBM.

CGPA- 7.14

PROJECTS

Optical Character Recognition WEBAPP API -

A Django based API to extract text from images.

Keylogger -

As a part of a cybersecurity project, developed a basic keylogger in python that could identify the keystrokes made in the victim's system.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- successfully won multiple national level hackathons.
- Led the team which got selected to pitch the startup idea in front of the Prime Minister of India.